Inventory of the Personal Papers and Official Records from the International Military Tribunal in the Far East, 1945-1948
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Personal Papers and Official Records from the International Military Tribunal in the Far East, 1945-1948
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 78-4
This collection consists of 86 boxes.
The G. Carrington Williams Papers document his work on the International Defense Section of the International Military Tribunal of the Far East from 1945 to 1948.
G. Carrington Williams
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
G. Carrington Williams, a 1942 graduate of the University of Virginia School of Law, was an International Defense Section (IDS) counsel for the International Military Tribunal for the Far East (IMTFE), also called the Tokyo War Crimes Trials. Williams was assigned the defense of Naoki Hoshino, who was the chief civilian official in the Japanese government for Manchuria, as president of the Planning Board, 1940-1941, and chief cabinet secretary, 1941-1944.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of Williams' personal files regarding the defense of Hoshino and the International Defense Section in general (boxes 1-5), as well as copies of documents, exhibits, the transcript of the proceedings and other trial records (boxes 6-86).
Contents List
- Defense counsel memos, letters 1946-1947 (Box 1)
- Memoranda, reports, and personal notes re Hoshino 1946-58 (Box 1)
- Indictment n.d. (Box 1)
- Peronnel Information n.d. (Box 1)
- Law Books n.d. (Box 1)
- Law committee memo n.d. (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous defense materials n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous interviews, motions n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous literature n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous newspaper cuttings 1947 (Box 2)
- Personal responsibility brief n.d. (Box 3)
- May motion of jurisdiction of tribunal 1946 (Box 3)
- Motion to dismiss on behalf of all defendants n.d. (Box 3)
- Rough draft motion to dismiss n.d. (Box 3)
- Proceedings in chambers 1947 Oct.-Nov. (Box 3)
- "Trial of War Criminals"--Nuremberg n.d. (Box 3)
- IPS Documents n.d. (Box 3)
- Pearl Harbor--Congressional Reports 1945 (Box 3)
- Memoirs of Konoye n.d. (Box 3)
- Yamashita opinions n.d. (Box 3)
- Class B and C materials n.d. (Box 3)
- Defense divisions n.d. (Box 4)
- Defense division--Pacific phase n.d. (Box 4)
- Opening statements of defense n.d. (Box 4)
- Trial Data n.d. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous indices of defense and prosecution exhibits [1946-1948] (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous trial transcripts [1946-1948] (Box 7)
- Exhibits (Numbers 1-3220, incomplete) [1946-1948] (Box 8-27)
- Defense documents (Numbers 1-2622, incomplete) [1946-1948] (Box 28-36)
- Documents 1-10500 (incomplete) [1946-1948] (Box 37-38)
- Proceedings of the IMTFE n.d. (Box 39-86)